Guide to the Lucy Maynard Salmon Papers, 1818-1992 (bulk 1854-1933)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Lucy Maynard Salmon Papers
1818-1992
1854-1933
Salmon, Lucy Maynard, 1853-1927
23 cubic feet (66 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
The Lucy Maynard Salmon Collection includes the personal papers of Lucy Maynard Salmon along with two smaller collections of papers belonging to her mother, Maria Clara Maynard Salmon, and her brother, Pomeroy L. Salmon. The materials relate to her work as an historian and professor at Vassar College as well as her work with the suffrage movement and local political issues. There are also materials relating to her family, education and personal life. Formats include correspondence, manuscripts, printed material, clippings, minutes, reports, notes, and photographs.
Biographical Note
Lucy Maynard Salmon, historian, was born in Fulton, NY, on 27 July 1853. After attending a local seminary, she entered the University of Michigan in 1872. Upon graduation she taught high school for five years, but tired of the monotony of small-town life and returned to Ann Arbor to earn her master's degree in modern European history, English, and American constitutional history. Following three unhappy years of teaching at Indiana State Normal School, she went to Bryn Mawr for graduate study in American history. In 1887 she became Vassar's first teacher of history and was made a full professor in 1889, remaining at Vassar for the rest of her career.
Modern history was a recent addition to the American college curriculum, and Miss Salmon was one of its most innovative teachers. Conducting her advanced classes as seminars, she encouraged students to do original research and to explore unconventional sources. Miss Salmon was instrumental in liberalizing Vassar's curriculum and administration. She stressed the importance of current affairs and the periodical press, and introduced classes on the newspaper and the use of historical materials, with particular emphasis on scholarly research techniques. Outside the history department she actively worked for a better library, fewer required courses, and greater influence of the faculty on the college administration.
Her publications, which included Domestic Service, The Newspaper and the Historian, and The Newspaper and Authority were expressive of her faith in democracy. Two books published posthumously, Why is History Rewritten? (1929) and Historical Material (1933), reflect her devotion to the "New History" of scholars like James Harvey Robinson. A pacifist and dedicated suffragist, Miss Salmon was a notable participant in local public affairs, in the American Historical Association, and in the Association of Collegiate Alumnae. She continued to be an active scholar and teacher until she suffered a fatal stroke in 1927. A biography, Apostle of Democracy: the Life of Lucy Maynard Salmon (1943), was written by her Vassar colleague, Louise Fargo Brown.
Chronology
27 July 1853 Born to George and Maria Clara Maynard Salmon in Fulton, NY
1868-1870 Attended Fulton Falley Seminary (formerly Fulton Female Seminary)
1871-1872 Attended Ann Arbor High School
1876 A.B. in history, University of Michigan
1876-1881 Principal of McGregor High School, McGregor, Iowa
1883 A.M. in modern European history, English, and American constitutional history, University of Michigan
1883-1886 Instructor in history at Indiana State Normal School
1886 Published "History of the Appointing Power of the President" (masters' thesis)
1886-1887 Fellow in American History, Bryn Mawr
1887 Appointed as associate professor of history at Vassar College
1889 Appointed as professor of history at Vassar College
1896-1899 Member of the Committee of Seven, American Historical Association
1897 Published Domestic Service
1898-1900 Leave of absence for study in Paris and Florence
1903 Founder and President (1904) of the Association of History Teachers of the Middle States and Maryland
1906 Published Progress in the Household
1912 Honorary Doctor of Literature Degree, Colgate University
1915-1919 Member of executive council of the American Historical Association
1923 Published The Newspaper and the Historian
1923 Published The Newspaper and the Authority
1926 Lucy Maynard Salmon Fund for Research established by students and friends
1927 Honorary Doctor of Letters degree, University of Michigan
14 February 1927 Died at age 73
1929 Published Why is History Rewritten? (posthumous)
1933 Published Historical Material (posthumous)
Scope and Content Note
The Lucy Maynard Salmon Collection includes the personal papers of Lucy Maynard Salmon along with two smaller collections of papers belonging to her mother, Maria Clara Maynard Salmon, and her brother, Pomeroy L. Salmon. Types of material represented in the collection include: incoming and outgoing correspondence; published and unpublished manuscripts; pamphlets, periodicals, news clippings (originals and photocopies), and other printed materials; diaries and journals; reminiscences and genealogies; and photographs.
A substantial portion of the Lucy Maynard Salmon Collection dates between 1887 and 1927, the years during which Lucy Maynard Salmon served on the Vassar College Faculty. Subjects covered by the collection include: the development of the history department at Vassar College; methods of teaching history; the use of original source materials in research; the women's suffrage movement; the University of Michigan; the Fulton Falley Seminary; home economics; domestic service; and other personal, family and profession issues.
There is also information about professional organizations such as the Association of Collegiate Alumnae, American Association of University Women, and the American Historical Association.
Correspondents include Caroline E. Page Salmon, Pomeroy Lyman Salmon, George Salmon, Lucy Ella Maynard Sloss, and other family members, 1859-1926; Henry Noble MacCracken, James Monroe Taylor, Louise Fargo Brown, Eloise Ellery, C. Mildred Thompson, and other Vassar associates, 1887-1927; Edith Rickert, Amelia MacDonald Cutler, Helena Grow Rottschaefer, and other Vassar students, 1890-1927; James Burrell Angell, Katharine Lee Bates, George Lincoln Burr, Alice Freeman Palmer, M. Carey Thomas, Lelia Y. Burt, H.V. Clulow, Rachel Larrabee, Gertrude H. Mason, and other educational and political contemporaries, 1870-1927; Adelaide Underhill, Vassar College Librarian with whom Salmon shared a house, 1894-1927, and condolence letters to Underhill on Salmon's death, 1927-1931; and round-robin letters from student social groups at the University of Michigan, "Q. Ceekers," and at Bryn Mawr, "The Learned Six," 1874-1893.
Papers of her mother, Maria Clara Maynard Salmon, include class notes, circa 1834, diaries and account books, 1840-1863, and correspondence with Miranda Smith Belden, George Salmon, James B. Maynard, Frederick W. Lyman, and Lucy Piper Maynard, 1831-1861.
Papers of her brother, Pomeroy Lyman Salmon, include correspondence with family and friends, primarily Pomeroy's parents, George Salmon and Maria Clara Maynard Salmon, and his son, Maynard Hubbard Salmon, as well as family records and documents, financial records, memorabilia, and published ephemera.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Names:
Angell, James Burrell, 1829-1916; Bates, Katharine Lee, 1859-1929; Belden, Miranda Smith; Brown, Louise Fargo; Burr, George Lincoln, 1857-1938; Burt, Lelia Y.; Clulow, H. V.; Cutler, Amelia MacDonald, 1882-1947; Ellery, Eloise, 1874-1958; Larrabee, Rachel; Lyman, Frederick W.; MacCracken, H. N. (Henry Noble), 1880-1970; Mason, Gertrude H.; Maynard, James B.; Maynard, Lucy Piper; Palmer, Alice Freeman, 1855-1902; Rickert, Edith, 1871-1938; Rottschaefer, Helena Grow; Salmon family; Salmon, Caroline E. Page; Salmon, George; Salmon, Maria Clara Maynard; Salmon, Maynard Hubbard, 1883-1949; Salmon, Pomeroy Lyman; Sloss, Lucy Ella Maynard; Taylor, James Monroe, 1848-1916; Thomas, M. Carey (Martha Carey), 1857-1935; Thompson, C. Mildred (Clara Mildred), 1881-1975; Underhill, Adelaide, 1860-1936
Organizations:
Vassar College. Department of History; Vassar College--Faculty; Vassar College--Students; Vassar College--Alumni and alumnae; University of Michigan--Students; University of Michigan. Q. Ceekers; Association of Collegiate Alumnae (U.S.); Bryn Mawr College--Students; Bryn Mawr College. Learned Six; American Association of University Women; American Historical Association; Falley Seminary (Fulton, N.Y.)
Subjects:
Family--New York (State) History--Study and teaching; Women--Suffrage; Home economics; History--Research; Education; Women's rights; Women--Diaries; Women's colleges--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie; Women's colleges--Pennsylvania--Bryn Mawr; Women and peace; Women--Societies and clubs; Women--Social conditions; Feminism; Feminists; Pacifists; Women college teachers
Places:
New York (State)--Genealogy; United States--Politics and government--19th century; United States--Politics and government--20th century
Document Types:
Account books; Correspondence; Diaries; Ephemera; Genealogies; Photographs; Realia
VCL Categories:
Family; History and Historians; Vassar College; Women's History
Encoding Information
Original encoding by Elizabeth Clarke, 2007. Updated by Mark Seidl, 2019. Updated by Emma Gronbeck, June 2023.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Estate of Lucy Maynard Salmon and contributions by relatives and friends, circa 1936.
Two albums of postcards from Sweden and Norway were transferred from the Vassar College History Department, 2012. [M2012-010]
One letter by Lucy Maynard Salmon was purchased from John Wilson Manuscripts, Ltd., 2019. [M2019-016]
Pomeroy L. Salmon addition was the gift of Jeffrey Salmon, 2023. [M2023-033]
Other Formats
Some items from the Salmon Papers are available electronically via the Vassar College Digital Library. The items were digitized as part a Hudson River Valley Heritage exhibit, Women of the Hudson Valley.
Series List
- Series I. Correspondence — Outgoing, 1854-1927
  This series contains letters from Lucy Maynard Salmon to others, arranged alphabetically.
  - a. Relatives
  - b. Vassar College Faculty, Trustees, and Administrators
  - c. Vassar College Students and Alumnae
  - d. Others
  - e. Round-Robin Letters
    This subseries includes all round-robin letters written by "Q. Ceekers" and "The Learned Six," social groups to which Lucy Maynard Salmon belonged at University of Michigan and Bryn Mawr, respectively.
- Series II. Correspondence — Incoming, 1859-1936
  This series contains letters to Lucy Maynard Salmon from others, arranged alphabetically.
  - a. To Relatives
  - b. Vassar College Faculty, Trustees, and Administrators
  - c. Vassar College Students and Alumnae
  - d. Historians
  - e. Others
- Series III. Correspondence — To and From Others, 1840-1943
  This series contains letters to and from family members, friends, colleagues, and acquaintances of Lucy Maynard Salmon to others.
  - a. To Adelaide Underhill
  - b. From Adelaide Underhill
  - c. Others to Others
- Series IV. Writings, 1861-1933
  This series consists of notes, drafts, and published copies of Lucy Maynard Salmon's writings, as well as related correspondence.
  - a. Manuscripts and Notes
  - b. Published Material
  - c. Correspondence Regarding Publications
- Series V. Biography and Personal, 1836-1976
  This series contains Lucy Maynard Salmon's personal journal; personal ephemera such as certificates; family documents and records; and printed and published materials about Salmon and her extended family.
  - a. General
  - b. Family and Genealogy
  - c. Education
  - d. Academic Positions
  - e. Death
  - f. Miscellaneous
- Series VI. Photographs, 1870s-1924
  This series consists of photographs of Lucy Maynard Salmon and her family, as well as some photographs of assorted other subjects.
- Series VII. Vassar College, 1888-1935
  This series contains records of Lucy Maynard Salmon's time at Vassar College as a member of the faculty. Includes committee correspondence and reports; correspondence with other faculty and administrators; correspondence with alumnae; materials concerning the Lucy Maynard Salmon Fund for Research; financial records of purchases made for the college library; course outlines and examinations; annual reports; and Vassar College publications.
  - a. General
  - b. History Department
  - c. Publications
- Series VIII. Research and Subject Files, 1884-1933
  This series consists of Lucy Maynard Salmon's collected files on various topics and research subjects. Also includes correspondence with various organizations and individuals related to file subjects.
  - a. History and Teaching
  - b. Domestic Service
  - c. Laundry Lists
  - d. Miscellaneous
- Series IX. Maria Clara Maynard, 1818-1940
  This series contains the papers of Lucy Maynard Salmon's mother, Maria Clara Maynard Salmon. Includes Maria Clara Maynard's personal diaries, correspondence, and class notes and ephemera from her education at Ipswich Female Seminary.
  - a. Biography
  - b. Education
  - c. Correspondence
    Letters written to Maria Clara Maynard Salmon are filed alphabetically by author. Multiple letters by a single author are arranged chronologically within this alphabetical arrangement. Letters written by Maria Clara Maynard Salmon are arranged in an alphabetical sequence according to the name of the recipient. Multiple letters to a single recipient are further arranged according to chronology.
- Series X. Miscellaneous, 1818-1933
  This series includes assorted other materials, including memorabilia and realia; notes and writings; published materials; legal documents; and photographs.
- Series XI. Pomeroy L. Salmon Papers, 1837-1992
  This series contains the papers of Lucy Maynard Salmon's brother, Pomeroy Lyman Salmon. Includes correspondence with family and friends, primarily Pomeroy's parents, George Salmon and Maria Clara Maynard Salmon, and his son, Maynard Hubbard Salmon. The letters were collected by Maynard Hubbard Salmon and many include notes in his hand. Other materials include family records and documents, financial records, memorabilia, and published ephemera.
  - a. Correspondence
  - b. Other Materials
Container List
- SERIES I. CORRESPONDENCE — OUTGOING
  - Lucy Maynard Salmon to Relatives
    - Fraser, Henry S., 1918-1927; (mostly typed copies) (Folder 46.41)
    - Fraser, Minnie, 1913-1927 (Folder 46.40)
    - Randolph, Lucile, 1896-1925 (Folders 46.30 - 46.35)
    - Salmon, Brainerd, undated (Folder 46.50)
    - Salmon, Caroline E. Page, with one 1874 letter and TS to Mr. Duffield, 1870-1876; (37 letters, 25 TS) (Folders 1.1 - 1.7)
    - Salmon, Frank (and Mrs. Kirtland Salmon), 1883-1927, undated (Folders 46.19 - 46.21)
    - Salmon, George, 1870-1871; (2 letters, 2 TS) (Folder 1.8)
    - Salmon, Pomeroy Lyman, 1854-1875; (62 letters, 11 TS, 1 enclosure, 2 postcards, 18 envelopes, 1 carbon copy) (Folders 1.9 - 1.14)
    - Salmon, Pomeroy Lyman, 1876-1883; (124 letters, 7 TS, 2 postcards) (Folders 2.1 - 2.11)
    - Sloss, Lucy Ella Maynard, 1862-1865; (4 letters, 4 TS) (Folder 2.12)
    - Other Relatives, 1870-1883, undated; (5 letters, 3 TS) (Folder 2.13)
  - Lucy Maynard Salmon to Vassar College Faculty, Trustees, and Administrators
    - Armstrong, Sarah Sheppard, [1918]; (1 letter) (Folder 3.5)
    - Barbour, Violet, 3 Oct 1922; (1 letter) (Folder 3.5)
    - Brown, Louise Fargo, 1919, 1925; (1 telegram, 2 letters) (Folder 3.5)
    - Cassat, Paul C., 16 Nov 1925; (1 letter) (Folder 3.5)
    - Chambers, Frank R., 29 Nov 1918; (1 letter) (Folder 3.5)
    - Cushing, Florence, 1914; (2 letters, 2 drafts) (Folder 3.1)
    - Davenport, Frances G., 1905-1907; (18 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 3.2)
    - Ellery, Eloise, 13 July 1899; (1 letter) (Folder 3.5)
    - Fisher, Constance (Mrs. J.P. Gibson, Jr.), [1920], undated; (1 letter, 1 transcript) (Folder 3.5)
    - "Friend,", 29 Sep 1924; (1 letter) (Folder 3.5)
    - Gardner, Julia G., Nov 1906; (1 letter) (Folder 3.5)
    - Hadley, Helen Morris (Mrs. Arthur Twining), 1906-1907; (2 letters, 1 transcript) (Folder 3.6)
    - Harrington, Carris Bemis (Mrs. William), 23 Oct 1918; (1 letter) (Folder 3.6)
    - Ingersoll, Elizabeth Latham (Mrs. Earle A. Pritchard), 9 Sep 1915; (1 letter) (Folder 3.6)
    - MacCracken, Henry Noble, 1915-1926; (4 letters, 1 photocopy) (Folder 3.3)
    - McCaleb, Ella, Feb 1906; (1 letter) (Folder 3.6)
    - Raymond, Miss, 1903; (1 letter) (Folder 3.7)
    - Reed, Amy L., 1914-1918; (4 letters) (Folder 3.7)
    - Strong, Augustus H., [1907]; (1 letter, 1 transcript) (Folder 3.7)
    - Taylor, James Monroe, 1902-1912; (5 letters, 1 draft, 1 TS) (Folder 3.4)
    - Thallon, Ida C., 1 Dec 1926; (1 letter) (Folder 3.7)
    - Thompson, C. Mildred, 1924-1925; (2 letters) (Folder 3.7)
    - Underhill, Adelaide, 1894-1926 (Folders 45.14 - 45.26)
    - Officers of the Dept of History, 1924; (2 letters) (Folder 3.7)
    - Vassar Miscellany New Editors, 24 Nov 1923; (1 letter) (Folder 3.7)
    - Explanation of Lantern Slides, 30 Mar 1898; (1 letter) (Folder 3.7)
    - Drafts of letters to VC Trustees, 1906; (6 drafts) (Folder 3.8)
  - Lucy Maynard Salmon to VC Students and Alumnae (See also boxes 45 and 57)
    - Bryant, Mary (VC 1915), 12 Apr 1914; (1 letter) (Folder 4.7)
    - Cutler, Amelia MacDonald (VC 1904), 1909-1917; (21 letters) (Folders 3.9 - 3.11)
    - Davis, Helen Gertrude (VC 1898), 16 Aug 1899; (1 letter) (Folder 4.7)
    - Folsom, Mary (VC 1923), 1923-1925; (8 letters, 1 TS) (Folder 3.12)
    - Fox, Grace E., 1922-1923; (2 letters, 1 transcript) (Folder 4.7)
    - Howe, Miss, 18 Jan 1896; (1 letter) (Folder 4.7)
    - Kendig, Mercer (VC 1915), 1914-1923; (4 letters) (Folder 4.7)
    - Lauder, Estelle, 1923; (2 letters) (Folder 4.8)
    - Lewis, Doctor, 1898; (1 letter, 1 transcript) (Folder 4.8)
    - Meigs, Dorothy E. (VC 1914), 1922-1926; (10 letters, 1 enclosure) (Folder 3.13)
    - Mineah, Mary (VC 1870), 1905-1925; (4 letters) (Folder 3.14)
    - Rickert, Edith (VC 1891), 1900-1922; (27 letters, 1 postcard, 13 TS) (Folders 4.1 - 4.4)
    - Rusch, Florence Dolliver (VC 1902), 25 Jan 1925; (1 letter) (Folder 4.8)
    - Schermerhorn, Elizabeth (VC 1889), 17 June 1924; (1 letter) (Folder 4.8)
    - Sinsabaugh, Henrietta (VC 1896), 1896-1925; (29 letters, 2 enclosures, 2 postcards) (Folders 4.5 - 4.6)
    - Strong, Eliza L. M. (VC 1888), 15 Oct 1915; (1 letter, 1 transcript) (Folder 4.8)
    - Taylor, Louise C. (VC 1897), 1923-1926; (5 letters, 3 transcripts) (Folder 4.8)
    - Ward, Vassie James Hill (VC 1897), 1899, 1913, 1917; (3 letters) (Folder 4.8)
    - Willard, Marion (VC 1914), 7 Aug 1916; (1 letter) (Folder 4.8)
  - Lucy Maynard Salmon to Others
    - "Anne,", 24 Nov 1898; (1 letter) (Folder 4.11)
    - Baker, Ray Stannard [re: Woodrow Wilson], 1926; (2 draft TS) (Folder 47.37)
    - Eisler, Robert, 13 Nov 1923; (1 letter) (Folder 4.11)
    - Elizabeth, 31 Oct 1871; (1 letter) (Folder 4.11)
    - Ellery, Mr., 5 Dec 1925; (1 letter) (Folder 4.11)
    - Emerick, Libbie, 1870-1872; (9 letters, 1 TS) (Folder 4.9)
    - Felinghuysen, J.S., 13 June 1918; (1 letter) (Folder 4.11)
    - Gould, Miss, 23 Jan 1896; (1 letter) (Folder 4.11)
    - Hill, Justina Robinson, 5 Mar 1890; (1 letter) (Folder 47.42)
    - Hodge, Mrs., 4 Jan 1897; (1 letter) (Folder 4.11)
    - Jameson, J. Franklin, 1895-1896, 1903; (3 letters, 1 transcript) (Folder 24.8)
    - Justice, Mr., 1908, 1918; (2 letters) (Folder 4.11)
    - Keen, Charles, 8 Aug 1912; (1 letter) (Folder 4.11)
    - Kellogg & Rose, 22 May 1918; (1 letter) (Folder 4.11)
    - Larrabee, Rachel, 1881-1900; (1 letter, 8 TS) (Folder 4.10)
    - Leighton, Mr., 10 Sep 1919; (1 letter) (Folder 4.11)
    - Officers and Faculty of the University of Michigan, 15 Sep 1913; (1 letter, 1 check) (Folder 4.11)
    - Merritt, Jesse F., 1926; (2 letters) (Folder 4.12)
    - [Parmly?], D.D., 7 Feb 1896; (1 letter) (Folder 4.12)
    - Paxson, Frederic L., 23 Mar 1908; (1 letter) (Folder 4.12)
    - Rosenfield, Ruth, 1922, 1924; (2 letters) (Folder 4.12)
    - Leslie, Mrs. F.A., 21 Dec 1923; (1 letter, 1 transcript) (Folder 4.12)
    - Palmer, A. Mitchell, 1 May 1919; (1 letter) (Folder 4.12)
    - Silver, Mrs. Dr., 19 Oct 1919; ( 1 letter) (Folder 4.11)
    - Smith, Mr., 4 Apr 1922; (1 letter) (Folder 4.12)
    - University of Michigan, 1926, undated; (12 postcards) (Folder 4.13)
    - Villard, Mr., 12 Nov 1920; (1 letter) (Folder 4.12)
    - Walsh, T.J., 4 Feb 1919; (1 letter) (Folder 4.12)
    - Whaley, Mrs. Samuel, 12 Oct 1874 - 19 Dec 1907 (Folder 46.15)
    - Williams, Alice, 1901, 1921; (5 letters) (Folder 4.12)
    - Wilson, Woodrow [re: Robert H. hunter, Poughkeepsie Postmaster], undated (Folder 47.35)
    - Wilson, Woodrow [re: J.H.M.A. Von Tilling], 1 June 1918 (Folder 47.36)
  - Round Robin Letters
    - LMS to "The Learned Six,", July-Dec 1887; (4 letters, 1 TS) (Folder 25.9)
    - LMS to "The Learned Six,", 1888-1890; (10 letters) (Folder 25.10)
    - LMS to "The Learned Six,", 1891-1893; (9 letters, 1 TS) (Folder 25.11)
    - Letters to "The Learned Six,", 1886-1893, undated; (5 letters, 1 poem) (Folder 25.12)
    - Letters to the "Q-Ceekers,", 1874-1875; (5 letters, 1 TS) (Folder 25.13)
- SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE — INCOMING
  - Relatives to Lucy Maynard Salmon
    - Bixby, Mabel Maynard, undated; (1 letter) (Folder 5.16)
    - Bond, Miriam Apthorp, 25 Aug 1919; (1 letter) (Folder 5.16)
    - Fraser, Elizabeth, 1900-1921 (Folder 46.45)
    - Fraser, Henry, 1915-1925 (Folders 46.42 - 46.43)
    - [Fraser?], Mary, 22 July 1866; (1 letter) (Folder 5.8)
    - Fraser, Minnie, 1906-1926, undated (Folders 46.44 - 46.45)
    - Gregg, Ella V. (cousin), 1886-1906 (Folder 5.14)
    - Jones, Gardner M., 1919-1923; (5 letters) (Folder 5.1)
    - Jones, Nathan, 21 Mar 1890; (1 letter) (Folder 5.1)
    - Lee, Agnes L., undated; (1 letter) (Folder 5.16)
    - Lyman, Frank H. (with telegram from Adelaide Underhill to Lucy Maynard Salmon), 1889-1920; (10 letters) (Folder 5.2)
    - Maynard, Colton, 1 Oct 1905; (1 letter) (Folder 5.16)
    - Maynard, Edd, 1888, 1894; (2 letters) (Folder 5.8)
    - Maynard, George C., 1876, 1891, 1905; (3 letters) (Folder 5.8)
    - Maynard, L. G., 4 Dec 1861; ( 1 letter) (Folder 5.8)
    - Maynard, Louis C. (U.S. District Court Clerk, Northern District, Texas), 24 Jan 1925; (1 letter) (Folder 5.16)
    - Maynard, Louis Calvin (with note from Ella L. Maynard), 1860-1871; (8 letters, 1 TS) (Folder 5.3)
    - Maynard, Lucy Sophy and Clara E., 1864-1905 (Folder 5.13)
    - Maynard, Lucy Warner, 23 May 1925; (1 letter) (Folder 5.8)
    - Nichols, H.E., 17 Dec 1901; (1 letter) (Folder 5.8)
    - Nichols, Mary H., 16 Mar [no year]; (1 letter) (Folder 5.8)
    - Orendorff, Margaret, 1925-1927 (Folder 5.15)
    - [Pines?], L. L., 13 June 1859; (1 letter) (Folder 5.16)
    - Pomeroy, Margaret S. and Kate Salmon, 1890-1922 (Folder 46.51)
    - Randolph, Lucile (Mrs. Jeptha F. Randolph), 1901-1936 (Folders 46.37 - 46.38)
    - Royce, Frank [grandson of Frank and Kirtland Salmon] with letter to A. Underhill, 1916-1926, 1933 (Folder 46.46)
    - Royce, Elizabeth S., 1916-1924 (Folder 46.47)
    - Royce, Knibloe, 1904-1926 (Folder 46.48)
    - Royce, W. S. and Bertha, 1901 and 1916 (Folder 46.49)
    - Salmon, Brainerd - with letter from LMS to Brainerd, 1886-1906, undated (Folder 46.50)
    - Salmon, Brainerd Pomeroy, 1899-1900; (2 letter) (Folder 5.8)
    - Salmon, Carolyn E., 1871-1876; (12 letters, 2 TS) (Folder 5.4)
    - Salmon, Edward (uncle), 1865, 1891; (2 letters) (Folder 5.9)
    - Salmon, George, 1871-1872; (5 letters, 5 TS) (Folder 5.5)